# 有骨头 有剔下来的肉头子
There are bones, there are heads of meat.
# 边角料 腔骨还有棒骨 什么都有
Trimmings, bones, leg bones, everything.
# 就是做菜剩下的东西
They are what's left over from cooking.
# 黄花 干口蘑 木耳 香菇
Daylily, Dried mushrooms, dried fungus, shiitake
# 这打卤面啊师父
It's marinade noodles, Master
# 什么打卤面啊
Wrong
# 不是打卤面是什么面
What kind of noodles?
# 烂肉面
Pulled meat noodles
# 我第一次知道烂肉面
First time I knew pulled meat noodles
# 是从电影《茶馆》里头
was in the movie “Teahouse”
# 香菇水留着 底下不能要
Keep the shiitake water except the bottom part.
# 口蘑水 也是
So is mushroom water
# 光要上边的 底下都不要
Just the top, not the bottom.
# 底下有沙子
There's sand at the bottom
# 这个菜是流传好多年的
It's a dish that's been around for years
# 支个棚 摆两张桌子就卖烂肉面
Put up a shed, set up two tables and that’s enough to sell noodles.
# 咱把这改一下刀 小魏
Let’s cut it here, Xiao Wei
# 今天咱这是提升版了师父
Today we have an upgrade version, Master.
# 原来没这么好的料
It didn’t have the nice ingredients before.
# 就是筋头巴脑 边边沿沿
Just trimmings
# 这个菜是必须得有口蘑的是吧
The mushroom is essential in this dish, right?
# 必须得有口蘑
Of course
# 过去打卤 好多都离不开口蘑
Mushroom is part of marinated noodles.
# 葱姜 大料 桂皮
green onions, ginger, star anise, cinnamon
# 这个肉让小亮连冲带泡都白了
The pork is nearly white after washing
# 里边的沫子就少多了 一会就不用焯了
There's less froth inside. We don’t have to blanch it later
# 黄酒 齐活
Huangjiu rice wine. That’s all!
# 高压锅压吧 因为时间的问题
Considering time, let’s use pressure cooker.
# 这是能让人吃饱又解馋的
It's the one that will fill you up and satisfy your cravings
# 其实烂肉面白煮也行
Actually, the pulled pork noodles can be cooked in plain water.
# 咱这里边再加点酱油也行
We can add a little soy sauce here.
# 来 40分钟到50分钟都可以
about 40-50 mins
# 越烂乎越好
It’s better to stew it longer.
# 花椒对这个菜影响很大的
Szechuan peppers are a big influence on this dish.
# 花椒油
Szechuan pepper oil
# 我就要这花椒油的香味
I want the aroma of pepper oil
# 打卤面 这面那面 它离不开这个
The noodles can’t without it.
# 这香味是慢慢让它释放出来
The scent is being released slowly
# 花椒的香只有这样出的才好
This is the only way to get the aroma of pepper.
# 小火你看见没有
Do you see that? Simmer it.
# 这花椒基本都黑了 就行了
Until the peppers are mostly black
# 这香气多好
That's a nice aroma
# 歇会吧 就等着拆骨肉了
Let's take a break. We're just waiting for the bone and meat.
# 不能太薄了 太薄了没口感了面
You can't make it too thin. It's too thin. It'll lose its texture.
# 三仔儿 齐活
Finish!
# 熟了 这可烂乎啊师父
It's done. It's very soft, Master
# 杠杠的这肉 没毛病 香啊师父
This meat is really good. It's delicious, Master.
# 你看一抖落就下来了 特别烂乎
Look at the way it came off. It's so soft.
# 这边晾着咱打卤
Leave it here.
# 花椒油 先煸葱花呗师父
Sichuan peppercorn oil. Stir in the green onion first
# 葱花炝锅
Stir-fry green onion
# 炝出香味煸口蘑 煸香菇
when aroma comes out we stir-fry mushroom and shiitake
# 黄花
Daylily
# 木耳
black fugus
# 酱油
soy sauce
# 黄酒
huangjiu rice wine
# 香菇水口蘑水
the mushroom and shiitake water
# 根儿不能要 有沙子
There are sands at the bottom. We don’t use it.
# 来两勺烂肉汤 好了
And two spoons broth. That’s it.
# 老抽让它调调色 行了
Use dark soy sauce to add some color
# 师父调汤 我把面煮上 两不耽误
Master makes the marinade and I boil the noddles.
# 这还有点白胡椒粉
Add some white pepper.
# 今儿这汤 鲜味十足
Today’s soup has strong umami taste
# 把拆骨肉搁进去
then add the pulled pork in it.
# 这能不好吃么 这够横的
Isn't this delicious? It's so good
# 好  面也差不多了
Okay, noodles are almost ready
# 烂肉面
Pulled pork noodles
# 是不是咕嘟时间越长越好吃
Is it true that the longer cooking process, the better it tastes?
# 差不多就得了
You need to balance.
# 面也好了 豪华版烂肉面
The noodles are ready. The superb pulled pork noodles.
# 出锅
Time to enjoy it!
# 真是烂肉 一碗烂肉面出锅了
How soft it is!
# 你得忒儿喽
The pulled pork noodles is ready! So good!
# 终于吃到《茶馆》里边的烂肉面了
Finally, the pulled pork noodles from "Teahouse is in my mouth.
# 拆骨肉你看 这个面这个卤
Look at the marinade.
# 我觉得跟咱们吃
I think it’s different from
# 正常打卤是不一样的
the common marinaded noodles.
# 一般的花椒油都是后呲的
Usually, the Sichuan pepper oil is used at the end
# 你看我拿花椒油打底子
but I used it at the beginning
# 我用温火慢慢的让花椒释放
simmer it to release the aroma
# 最后炸到花椒有点糊了
until they are black
# 花椒那种淡淡的那种香气味
the gentle aroma from Sichuan peppercorn
# 然后用这个再煸葱花煸菌类
then use it to stir fry green onion and mushrooms
# 然后淡化花椒油的味 似有似无
so the aroma of Sichuan pepper is subtle
# 这跟后呲截然不同
the results are totally different
# 后边呲全是花椒油的味
You will get strong pepper taste if it is used in the last
# 又学一招师父 感谢
I learnt a new trick Master, Thanks
# 师弟 走
Come on brother
# 你们吃吧 最后一口
You guys eat it.
# 吃的满头大汗
You are sweating out on your head.